LINUS JOHANNESSON

Tel: 070-79 79 238 | Email: linusj555@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Stockholm

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer with focus on JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Vue, and Next.js for frontend, and Node.js and Express.js for backend. Familiar with databases like PostgreSQL, MySQL, and MongoDB, with experience in AWS, Docker, and Firebase for DevOps. Teaching Git at workshops. Experienced in collaboration tools like Jira and GitHub Project Pages, as well as UI design with Figma. Second Vice President of Chas Academy Student Corps.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer (Pro Bono), Osynlig | Stockholm



June 2024 –present

Part of a small team developing the project Föreningslivet, which aims to combat social exclusion and help people find inclusive activities through local associations. The tech stack includes **React** and **MongoDB** and it is hosted on **Fly.io** and **Vercel**." I worked on updating from NEXT.JS 12 to 14 and had an advisory role for my fellow student that also worked on the project.

Teaching, Chas Academy | Stockholm

Feb 2023 –present

Giving workshops on Git, GitHub and project management-tools.

Physiotherapist, Medfit | Stockholm

Aug 2018 – Aug 2023

Clinical work with patients. Responsible for inhouse professional training for all occupational groups at Medfits three facilities. Including planning, communication, public relations and budget.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Vue, Next.JS, Redux, Axios, HTML, CSS, Sass, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Vite. Backend: Node.JS, Express.JS. Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, Prisma, MongoDB, Mongoose. DevOps & Cloud: AWS, Docker, Firebase. Version Control & Collaboration: GIT, GitHub, GitLab, GitHub Project Page, Jira, Confluence, Slack, Notion. Design & UI Tools: Figma. IDEs & Tools:VS Code, NPM. APIs & Data Fetching: REST API, GraphQL

EDUCATION

Full-stack JavaScript, Chas Academy | Stockholm

June 2023 – present

PROJECTS

ShouldAlSign, personal project



September 2024 -present

Combining my current passion-project with an about me section. User agreements are hard to grasp which inspired me to develop a service that can help users understand what they sign. Frontend: Vite, React, Typescript. Backend: GraphQL, Mongoose, React, Typescript, Jsonwebtoken, Bcrypt, Express, OpenAI-API. DB: Atlas MongoDB. Hosted on AWS EC2 using Nginx as webserver. Domain from GleSys.

Babster, Chas Academy | Stockholm



Spring 2024

Students from Fullstack-Javascript, .Net, DevOps and UX/UI worked together to build Babster. My role was to build the chat-component and integrate OpenAls API as well as some promt-enginering to design what was sent to OpenAi aswell as what was returned to the chat-component. I also acted as scrum-master and was responsible for our Github-pages during the project

Portfolio, Sofia Masrour | Stockholm



September 2024 – present

Sofia is an architect who needs to showcase her work. I am building it with Vue to add skills to my repertoire. I like working with a designer and implement their design into code. I find it both easier and harder to have someone else's opinion on design than just my own. I hope Sofia will be happy with the final result.

CI/CD Pipeline, Chas Academy | Stockholm



Spring 2024

I created Dockerfiles for the Playwright tests and for the codebase, as well as a YML file for running both images in a container locally for testing the codebase. I also integrated the pipeline in Github Actions, so that creating a pull-request triggers the pushed code to be tested with AWS CodeGuru. Confirming the Pullrequest then triggers the deployment to AWS Elastic Beanstalk.